How's everybody doing?
>> Good. How are you? How are you? Did
>> you have a good weekend?
>> All right.
>> What the weekend you guys had?
>> Yeah.
>> Fast and furious.
>> What you got?
>> Um, how did the draft experience work
for you overall? Uh, just the first
month with you guys together.
I would say it was
collaborative, cohesive. Um, felt like
we executed
and I, you know, I think again, like I
told you last night, I think we helped
the Miami Dolphins. It was, it was a
great experience. It really was. Um,
we're we're very excited. I think I
speak for both both of us when we talk
about, you know, the excitement of the
the players that we drafted, uh, the
culture that we're trying to build. And,
uh, you know, number one, they can play.
You know, don't don't ever mistake that.
We're not going to bring guys in here
that we don't think can play on the
field, but then when you talk about the
wiring of the individuals, we feel like
we accomplished what we set out to
accomplish.
>> Yeah. I mean, I just start off I I think
John, Eric, and um that entire staff did
an incredible job. Um the work that they
put in, the process for me to sit in
there for the first time really in a
full draft rather than just on one side
of the football, it was really cool to
see. Um, incredible process, the
communication, the collaboration in
there, just sticking to all the hard
work that they had already done and and
watching, you know, the guys kind of
fall in place. Um, it was really cool
for me to see. Again, I I think he did
an unbelievable job in his first draft.
Um, very very excited about the players
that we picked and I can't wait to coach
them. So, just uh cool experience and
really excited about the players that we
got.
>> So, there's this trend. And I think you
had four or five sets of college
teammates now drafted here. Was that
coincidence or is that ever factored
into the equation when you're making
these picks?
>> Purely coincidence, you know, purely
coincidence. It's cool. It's a cool
story. Um, but no, that there was there
there was no agenda or intent there. It
just happened.
>> Speaking of agendas, it was or no
agendas rather. It's hard not to notice
that there's one particular state you
seem to draw players from. What can you
tell us about that?
>> Again, um you know, we let the board
talk to us and it's the best player
available approach and it just again
it's coincidence that that we had a lot
of guys from the state of Texas this
year. Uh they play good football in
Texas. So, you know, I think that's
probably a good thing, but again, there
was nothing that was intentional. It's
just the way that it kind of fell.
>> How much of a of a priority was
physicality in selecting the players?
>> Uh it's always a priority. You know, I
think we've talked about from the jump
just what we're trying to build here,
uh, the culture, the competition, and
then on top of that, uh, the play style.
I'll let him speak to the play style,
but I can tell you from the moment that
we started working together back in
Green Bay, he's he, you know, he says
that word or that phrase quite a bit
and, uh, and the players adhere to it.
Play style and physicality is a big part
of what we're trying to accomplish and
build here.
>> Yeah. I mean, I just, you know, if
there's one thing I told him when he
asked me my opinion on things, it's one
thing I I was not going to back away
from. I just I believe this is a
physical game and you need tough guys to
play this game and guys who want to be
physical. And I think if you look at
this list and you watch how hard these
guys play, I think it's impressive. And
what really that that says to me, it's
and I've said this before, you can find
out if a guy loves football based on how
hard he plays. you can find out how much
a guy loves his teammates based on how
hard he plays. And when you look at
this, I I think we got the right type of
guys and I'm excited to work with them.
>> So, you previously talked about the
quarterback position um infusing
competition into that room, potentially
dropping QB every year. Um how close
were you to go in QB? Why ultimately
decided not to? And where are you on the
competition in that room right now?
>> Sure. Uh good question. Um I I did say
that and it came up a couple times
throughout the course of the weekend. Um
it just we felt like the better option
was the other pick. Um just a chance for
for a guy to get on the field and help
us this year uh with where we are as a
roster. Um but the conversation happened
multiple times. Um I you know I'm
certainly not backing off what I said
initially. We we will take a a
quarterback every year, every other year
when we have the opportunity. Um, but we
just the way that it fell this year. And
part of that is we we like our room. You
know, we're we're happy with Malik, you
know, Quinn is is doing a good job and
will continue to do a good job and and
we like our number three as well. So,
we're we're in good shape there. Uh, and
just the way the board fell, it just it
didn't work out this year. But, uh, you
know, we'll take one next year, if not
the year after that. I've got a question
about um BPA and conviction and um BPA
and conviction I guess over need and I
want to see if I have examples correct
here. You guys uh took Proctor over
Ruben Bane when you needed an edge
rusher but BPA and conviction. You take
Jacob Rodriguez uh over uh Derek Moore
and Zion Young. BPA over conviction and
competition. You've got three. You had
two starting offensive tackles. You had
two starting inside linebackers. Do I am
I reading that right? Is that are those
examples of BPA and and over and
conviction over need?
>> Yeah. I mean, and those other guys,
again, I want to be I want to make sure
I'm being very clear here. You know,
those other other guys that you
mentioned are very good football players
and the Dolphins would have been lucky
to have them, but yeah, it is a best
player available approach and there's a
lot of conversations that go into it.
Um,
I just you don't you never have any way
of knowing what your needs are going to
be. You know, I've said that to you
before and and I believe that in my
heart of hearts. I mean, you can you can
have an embarrassment of riches in a
room and then you got a hamstring and an
ankle and now you're going to your
emergency board. So, um, we we took the
players that we felt like were the best
for the Miami Dolphins. Uh, that's no
shot at anybody that didn't end up here.
I'm sure they'll go on to have wonderful
careers and we wish them nothing but the
best, but we're very happy with who we
who we took and who we wound up with.
>> Was there a point in the draft where you
might have considered German McCoy or
did you guys have a medically red flag?
>> Uh, you know what? I he's a wonderful uh
talent and and a really good kid and uh
I'm going stay away from talking about
the medical of of anybody or any players
up here, but uh you know, I wish him the
best. I hope he has a great career.
>> Can you speak to your process now of
adding uh undrafted guys? Um, I guess
you can get a handful since you already
had 13 draft picks. Uh, and how much of
that has already happened?
>> Yeah, there it's it's going on as we
speak. You know, it's always a fast and
furious process postdraft. Um, you know,
we have we have our targeted guys and uh
and we're in the process of trying to
lock those guys up currently.
>> About how many might you have room for?
>> Uh, it's it's a fluid number. Um,
probably I would say eight to 10, you
know, just depending on how that goes.
One of the more interesting picks I
thought was Trayori. The Dolphins have
had I hope I pronounced it right.
>> Dolphins have had pathway players
before, but not drafted pathway players.
So, what attracted you to him and how
quickly how where do you see him in his
development right now?
>> Yeah, he's a he's kind of a very raw
athletic ball of clay, if you will. Um,
he's he can move, you know, he's he's an
interesting athlete. He's got twitch,
he's got speed, he's got good hands. I
think he's a he's a mismatch as a route
runner and uh and he should only get
better. You know, he hadn't been playing
football real long. So, um you know,
that that was what was intriguing to us,
especially at that value. Uh we felt
like a player who's who's ascending and
whose best ball is in front of him and
uh and can and can be a problem for
defenses in time. You know, I have a lot
of faith in the coaches who are going to
coach him every day to continue to
develop him as a pro. Um, but he, you
know, he was he was a somebody that we
had our eyes on for a while and he fell
to us at the right value, so we took a
shot.
>> Jeff, are there one or two tangible
qualities where the Dolphins got better
through the draft, whether it's um, you
know, competition or speed or size or
anything along those lines?
>> Well, yeah. I mean, I think we added
competition throughout our whole roster
and I think that's what you're looking
for. I think that brings out the best.
And I mean, you could look at all these
players and there's different qualities
that each of them have and there's
different reasons we like some of these
players over others. Um, but like we
said, competition is going to be the
key. Uh, these these 13 players bring
that as well as the guys that we have
right now on the roster. They'll be here
not this week, but the week after, and
we'll kind of get them acclimated and
then mix a team together, and I'm
excited to do that. Do you envision
giving Proctor, no matter where he ends
up, do you envision giving him looks at
guard and tackle on the spring and
summer?
>> Yeah, for sure. I I think, you know, we
we'll sit down and talk, you know, where
the best available position for him will
be. I think ultimately our job is to get
the best five on the field and however
that shakes out, um, it's our job to
figure that out. um extremely talented
player who can do both, which I think is
a plus anytime you have versatility in a
player. Um I think he can excel at both.
We we'll figure out where the best spot
is for him, you know, soon as we get on
the field.
>> Speaking of versatility, you picked a
few guys day three and Trey Moore and
Kyle Lewis that are kind of viewed as
tweeners, right? I'm curious how their
versatility um will play a role in your
defense.
>> That excites me. I think anytime you can
draft a player who can do multiple
things, it's our job as coaches to have
a vision for him and figure out where to
play him or play him in multiple spots.
What's a down and distance? What's he
going to do on early downs? Is he going
to be a stack backer on early downs? Is
he going to be a sub rusher uh in
second, seven plus, third down? Is he a
guy that can line up as a spinner and
pick guards and rush? Um and then you
look at the other guy. Can he can he
play outside backer? Can he play inside
backer? Can you insert him in different
spots on the field? Um, you know, the
great part about our conversations is if
you find a really good football player,
and I mean, smart guy, tough guy, a
productive player that jumps out on
tape, I think it's our job as coaches to
have a vision for him. And then I think
it's our job schematically to figure out
how to make it work for him. And I think
sometimes coaches look at we're playing
34, we're playing 4-3, and he doesn't
fit the scheme. I mean, I just I don't
agree with that. I mean, let's get the
best football players we can and let's
figure out what they can do. And now
it's going to be fun trying to figure
out these guys as we watch them do
individual and then we watch them play
football to figure out how to make it
work. Um, and that excites me as a coach
and I've said that before and I think
we've got a lot of pieces now to do
that. And I just I was sitting there
today in the draft meeting. I even
showed him I was like drawing up
different things different guys can do
like that. That's fun for me. And these
are really good players that mixed in
with the players that we have now. It's
our job to go to work and go through the
OTAAS and go through training camp and
by preeason, you know, we'll see what we
can do with them.
>> On the same topic on the other side of
the ball, you guys added a bunch of
players on the O line, tight end that
really can play downhill in a foam booth
and they have other skills as well, but
you also inherit a bunch of guys that
have excelled at outside zone scheme.
How important was it to you guys to
diversify what you can do from a running
game scheme standpoint? Well, I think
the guys that we have can run outside
zone, can run inside zone, and can run
gap scheme. I just I think it's the same
thing that I just said. Um, the more we
can do, the more our players can do, and
then let's figure out what they do best
and let's go get good at it.
>> Jeeoff, we heard Sullie's comments on
Chris Johnson, but I want to go back to
some things you said about how you scout
quarterbacks um at the league meetings.
You know, the the three levels of play.
when you're watching Chris Shantton
play, you know, how did he fare at all
three levels?
>> No, it's it's it's cool that you
remember that. I think he can win at all
three and he can take the ball away and
he tackles and he's aggressive and I
love his play style and he can play
inside. I mean, this was one of my
favorite guys in the draft that when we
started talking about him and it came
time to pick him. I mean, I I would not
have been surprised if he was taken
earlier than we took him. So, he can win
at those levels. I'm excited to coach
him. He was here yesterday. Um, he's got
good size to him. He's got length to
him. He's a great person. He loves
football. I am very excited to get a
chance to coach him.
When it comes to edge rusher, did you
hope to maybe get one in in-house in the
first two days? And then how did you
feel about coming away with the two you
did get here on day three?
>> I I just wanted the best player
available and I think that's the cool
part about this draft and the process
and really learning from him and going
through this the first time. Um, and it
kept coming back to that as we talked.
It's do you take this? No, just keep
taking the best player you can. and we
did that and we stuck to it and I think
that will help our team as we go
forward. Um and then the other guys that
we took really excited about them. I
mean guys that have versatility um you
know at the end Max has got a toughness
to him that we liked. He's a rugged
player. He plays really hard. Um and
then even like a guy like Trey Moore,
right? All the things that Trey can do.
The amount of sacks that he's had in his
career, the ability to play linebacker,
the ability to play off the edge. I mean
that's really exciting for us. So, I
look forward to seeing those guys and
coaching them.
>> I think when if I can chime in here, you
know, the theme is good football players
who can do different things. And as you
build a roster, injuries, it's
inevitable. Injuries are going to
happen. So, it's no different than in
life, right? The more you can do, the
more value you bring. Um, and that was
kind of, you know, that's been our theme
all the way through. Let's let's just
collect as many really good football
players as we can who can do a lot of
different things, throw them in the mix,
and good things will happen. You know,
that that are also I know you guys are
tired of hearing me use the phrase wired
right, but that are wired right. You
know, that that love what they do and
are passionate about what they do and
have leadership skills and physical and
mental toughness. And you're not going
to go wrong that way. You know, you can
win with with with uh with that with
that mindset and win with that that
process. I believe that my heart of
hearts
>> and I think you know and I agree with
Sully I think what should excite people
and what's exciting to us as coaches I
mean as I look at these names these are
good not only good football players but
a they're smart football players they're
tough football players it's going to be
cool to see this group mixed together u
because I think they all have a very
similar mindset and I think they all
have a little bit of edge to them and
that that excites excites me to start
coaching.
>> Now that you guys have this full picture
for the draft class and you try to
define the scheme, right, is does it
work as starting broad and getting more
narrow or is it a matter of starting
narrow and then building it out once you
kind of get a feel for the guys?
>> Well, I think we have right now and you
know, Bobby on offense and obviously I
have a I'll have a saying that as well
and in our defense with Shawn. I mean,
we have a
um we have a system that we're going to
run, but there's tweaks within a system
and there's evolutions within a system
and there's things that we'll think
outside the box to add to the system.
But in general, we we've got a really
good solid core foundation of the
systems that we're going to run that are
in place and we've already started
teaching to the guys that are here
because let's not forget, we've got some
we've got some good pieces here already
that have been working really hard and
doing a really really good job. Um, and
we had two really good days of mini camp
out there. So, this isn't reinventing an
offense or a defense. This is now
plugging in players to see who does what
best and creating some really really
good competition, which that is what
excites me the most. Anytime you can add
add that, you're going to bring out the
best in these guys.
>> For an entire secondary that needs to be
rebuilt, I mean, you you guys basically
partied ways with just about every
starter. Why only one quarterback and
why one safety?
>> We like we like a lot of the guys that
we have. Um we've got to spend time with
them. We have some guys that were
injured last year that are back and
we've got to watch them on the field and
then um same with some safeties. We
brought in some guys. There's guys that
were here and you know we did we added
obviously we added a safety. We added
Chris and then really even getting Kyle
who's got the versatility. I know he's
listed as a linebacker, but I think
you're going to see him move around and
do some things back there as well.
>> Um, when you guys talk a lot about size,
toughness, versatility, the only player
that I guess doesn't necessarily Well, I
don't want to speak on the toughness
part of it because, you know, we'll
learn that over time, but I guess size
and versatility. Kevin Coleman is the
only player that immediately comes to
mind that doesn't necessarily fit those.
I'm curious what you guys saw out of
him.
>> Sure. It was just it was an opportunity
to add some explosiveness to the
offense, some speed, guy that's uh again
versatile, can return, you know, help
you in the return game. Um, and has been
a good player in in in in the most
competitive league in college football
in the SEC, or at least in my opinion.
Um, so yeah, it was it was just again an
opportunity to add some speed, some
juice to that position group. Uh, and a
guy that that we think can can do
multiple things.
a question.
>> All right, guys.
>> Thanks, guys. Enjoy your weekend.
>> Take care.